<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>flopska.com</title><link href="https://flopska.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://flopska.com/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://flopska.com/</id><updated>2017-05-06T00:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>Overnight Sensations Build Log - Baffles</title><link href="https://flopska.com/overnight-sensations-build-log-baffles.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-06T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-05-06T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>flopska</name></author><id>tag:flopska.com,2017-05-06:/overnight-sensations-build-log-baffles.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the second part of a multipart post. It features pictures of the process of routing the baffles.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Einhell Router" src="https://flopska.com/images/overnightsensations/router.JPG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Routing the baffles&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Baffle with cutout for the woofer" src="https://flopska.com/images/overnightsensations/baffle_sub.JPG"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Baffle with cutout for the woofer" src="https://flopska.com/images/overnightsensations/baffle_sub_2.JPG"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Baffle 10mm round edge" src="https://flopska.com/images/overnightsensations/baffle_edges.JPG"&gt;
&lt;img alt="Finished Baffles" src="https://flopska.com/images/overnightsensations/baffles_finished.JPG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Overnight Sensations Build Log - Cabinets</title><link href="https://flopska.com/overnight-sensations-build-log-cabinets.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-05-03T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2017-05-03T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>flopska</name></author><id>tag:flopska.com,2017-05-03:/overnight-sensations-build-log-cabinets.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is the first part of a multi-part post and shows how the cabinets are constructed. Measurements for the cabinet parts are given.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Makita Circular Saw" src="https://flopska.com/images/overnightsensations/saw.JPG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With my girlfriend travelling through Europe and some spare time on my hands I
decided to build some &lt;a href="https://sites.google.com/site/undefinition/diy-overnightsensations"&gt;Overnight
Sensations&lt;/a&gt;
for her. The design is by the one and only Paul Carmody - I'm still impressed
by his Speedster speakers which sit unfinished on my desk because I can't stop
listening to them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Parts for the cabinets&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 x 23,0cm x 15,4cm x 1,2cm &lt;em&gt;Front&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 x 15,3cm x 19,1cm x 1,2cm &lt;em&gt;Top / Bottom&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 x 19,1cm x 22,9cm x 1,2cm &lt;em&gt;Sides&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 x 12,9cm x 20,5cm x 1,2cm &lt;em&gt;Back&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The front is a bit larger than necessary so it's possible to flush-trim it later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Building the cabinets&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got the wood cut to the right sizes directly at the hardware store. At home I
used a handheld circular saw to cut the edges to 45°.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="45° Cut" src="https://flopska.com/images/overnightsensations/degree_cut.JPG"&gt;
&lt;img alt="All parts together" src="https://flopska.com/images/overnightsensations/all_parts.JPG"&gt;
The angle was set using a triangle because the scale on the saw is a bit off.
The cut is not perfect - a table saw would be better but I can live with the
result. I think the main problem is the missing guide rail but those things are
expensive...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step is to glue the sides together. Here the mitred edges come into
play: Instead of clamping the cabinet it is possible to use tension belts.
This has the benefit of a perfectly square box shortening the time spend
sanding the edges and greatly simplifying the veneering afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Clamping the box" src="https://flopska.com/images/overnightsensations/tension_belt.JPG"&gt;
With the edges appearently not being 45 degrees straight there is a small gap
between the parts. This has to be levelled later and shows how a better
preparation would've payed of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up is cutting the holes for the terminals and the bass reflex in the back,
using a holesaw this is straightforward. The diameters are 5cm and 4,5cm
respectively.
&lt;img alt="Cutting holes in the back" src="https://flopska.com/images/overnightsensations/back.JPG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only one step left, putting the backs in... They fit very well, the mitred
edges seem to work. After sanding everything to make it level, filling the
edges with my glue / sanding-dust combination, sanding, filling and sanding
again, this is how they look:
&lt;img alt="Putting it all together" src="https://flopska.com/images/overnightsensations/cabinets_glued.JPG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up are the baffles and the veneering.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Next Stop... Fontainebleau</title><link href="https://flopska.com/next-stop-fontainebleau.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-12-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-12-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>flopska</name></author><id>tag:flopska.com,2015-12-18:/next-stop-fontainebleau.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My plan for Fontainebleau was clear: Do something for my Karma and send this boulder from Fred Nicole! Made famous by Ben Moon's and Jerry Moffat's &lt;em&gt;The Real Thing&lt;/em&gt; everyone knows about this kind of special 8a+ in the forest. I wanted to give it a shot at least...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My plan for Fontainebleau was clear: Do something for my Karma and send this boulder from Fred Nicole! Made famous by Ben Moon's and Jerry Moffat's &lt;em&gt;The Real Thing&lt;/em&gt; everyone knows about this kind of special 8a+ in the forest. I wanted to give it a shot at least...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We (Thomas and myself) arrived at Fontainebleau in the dark after a heart-stopping moment where the van got stuck in the wet meadow next to the highway when I tried to turn round because we missed the exit. Luckily Thomas was able to push the car forward till it unstuck. The rest of the drive was boring in comparison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The area is famous for its shit wheather. We experienced it so-so: It didn't rain and the sun came out frequently but somehow a lot of the boulders stayed wet. Appearently it rained &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; before we arrived and I believe the soaked ground did its magic to keep everything from drying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We still had a lot of fun on the dry or partly dry boulders and Fontainebleau showed us once more just how difficult the different grades are. Being shut down on Karma (I could do the first move but had no chance on the second one) we explored the different areas a bit and tried a lot of the problems in the 5+6 guidebook. Sadly we didn't take many pictures :( For me the best day was the one where we tried to climb the red parcour in the Bas Cuvier area. We didn't manage it completely but the diversity of the problems in the parcour is just awesome: slabs, roofs, vertical climbing and there's even a crack-problem in it. Next time we'll do it fully :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Thomas in Fontainebleau, making quick work of Beatle Juice" src="https://flopska.com/images/thomas_bleau.jpg"&gt;
Thomas making quick work of &lt;em&gt;Beatle Juice 7a+&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our takeaways from the trip: Don't go to the swimming pool in Arbonne-la-forêt to take a shower: It's expensive, they don't allow you to wear regular swimming pants, they don't have nice showers and the pool itself is very small. The shower at &lt;a href="http://www.fontaineblhostel.com/"&gt;Fontaineblhostel&lt;/a&gt; on the other hand is very nice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn't manage to climb Karma, I put three sessions into it but couldn't do the second move. I will come back stronger.    &lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>I am featured in a climbing video?!</title><link href="https://flopska.com/i-am-featured-in-a-climbing-video.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-11-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-11-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>flopska</name></author><id>tag:flopska.com,2015-11-01:/i-am-featured-in-a-climbing-video.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After the trip to Italy I planned to visit a friend in Rosenheim. Driving there I stopped in Chironico and tried some more boulders. I arrived late at night and directly went to sleep. The next morning I got to know some Spaniards living in Zürich and we went to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After the trip to Italy I planned to visit a friend in Rosenheim. Driving there I stopped in Chironico and tried some more boulders. I arrived late at night and directly went to sleep. The next morning I got to know some Spaniards living in Zürich and we went to try &lt;em&gt;Confessions of a crap artist 7c+&lt;/em&gt;. We did some moves on &lt;em&gt;Matusalem 6c+&lt;/em&gt; to warmup and &lt;a href="Edoardo Moruzzi"&gt;http://www.edoardomoruzzi.com/&lt;/a&gt; captured some of it on video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/143742361?color=ffffff&amp;portrait=0" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://vimeo.com/143742361"&gt;Climbing Vibes&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href="https://vimeo.com/edoardomoruzzi"&gt;Edoardo Moruzzi&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="https://vimeo.com"&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards we drove to the upper area and tried &lt;em&gt;Vitruvian Man&lt;/em&gt; which is a bit of a weird boulder: Someone chipped a large jug into the roof which turned the 7c problem into a 7a-ish one. You can still climb the 7c but you have to use a rather small crimp next to the jug. I climbed the 7a a few years ago so I went for the 7c. Being able to do all of the three single moves I thought it would be easy to link them - somehow the boulder escaped me, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day I played on &lt;em&gt;Freak Brothers 8a&lt;/em&gt; for a short time but being really exhausted from the trip to Italy and the bouldering the day before I continued my drive to Rosenheim where I was welcomed with an awesome pizza.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Monte Cucco - First visit to Finale and Varazze in Italy</title><link href="https://flopska.com/monte-cucco-first-visit-to-finale-and-varazze-in-italy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-28T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-10-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>flopska</name></author><id>tag:flopska.com,2015-10-28:/monte-cucco-first-visit-to-finale-and-varazze-in-italy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I bought my Van (a VW T4 Transporter) at the end of September. A few people from the climbing gym in Karlsruhe went to Finale at the start of October and I planned to join them there when I finished my camper conversion. Sebastian, a friend of mine, had some …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I bought my Van (a VW T4 Transporter) at the end of September. A few people from the climbing gym in Karlsruhe went to Finale at the start of October and I planned to join them there when I finished my camper conversion. Sebastian, a friend of mine, had some spare time on his hands and we decided to drive together to Italy.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I raced the camper conversion but it turned out to work well anyways. After an exhausting drive we arrived at the camping in the dark and fell to sleep in an instant. The next morning we met the rest of the people from Karlsruhe and after a short breakfast went climbing together. Having slept only 4 hours our climbing looked more like this:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Resting after a long drive" src="https://flopska.com/images/sebastian_hammock.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did some easy climbing that day and tried to get used to the rock. The weather was perfect to rest in the sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Varazze&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some climbing the following days a few people decided to drive to Varazze which is around 30 minutes away from the campsite. The picture shows Alex bouldering a 6c on the Gioia boulder which sits right at the beginning of the area.
&lt;img alt="Alex in Varazze" src="https://flopska.com/images/alex_varazze_edited.JPG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We enjoyed some of the easier boulders there and I started to work the moves of &lt;em&gt;Messa Delle Streghe (7c)&lt;/em&gt; which escaped me that day. On a site note it's appearently possible to climb the upper part of the problem, too. When I understand the guidebook correctly it's graded &lt;em&gt;7c+&lt;/em&gt; when you do the highball exit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Finale&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up was some climbing in the Alveare sector in Finale. The sector is the home of the two famous routes &lt;em&gt;Viaggio Nel Futuro 7c+&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Hyaena 8b/+&lt;/em&gt;. The sun is burning into it so it might be better to go there on a cloudy day but we enjoyed the time in the sun and worked our tan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the guidebook &lt;em&gt;Viaggio&lt;/em&gt; was supposed to be Finale's first 8a but after someone found new beta it turned out to be &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; 7c+. I still think it's very hard :).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Trying the super classic viaggio nel Futuro" src="https://flopska.com/images/flo_viaggio_instagram.JPG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the next week I went there two more times but was not able to climb it because I kept falling off the dyno to the huge jug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the rest of the people from Karlsruhe left for the drive back home I met two guys from Augsburg, Germany: Benny and Chris. It turned out they know the same people in Karlsruhe I know - of course we went climbing together. When we weren't climbing we had awesome meals and some good talks going on.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Short 4 Day Trip To Magic Wood</title><link href="https://flopska.com/short-4-day-trip-to-magic-wood.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-09-06T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2015-09-06T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>flopska</name></author><id>tag:flopska.com,2015-09-06:/short-4-day-trip-to-magic-wood.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Patrick, Lukas and I went to Magic Wood from 24.07 to 27.7 again. Patrick had a
car from his parents and we all had some free time and a lot of psyche to try
ourselves on some of Avers' classics. With the unspoken goal of finally
climbing our …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Patrick, Lukas and I went to Magic Wood from 24.07 to 27.7 again. Patrick had a
car from his parents and we all had some free time and a lot of psyche to try
ourselves on some of Avers' classics. With the unspoken goal of finally
climbing our first 8a we arrived friday noon and set out to try &lt;em&gt;Foxy Lady
(8a)&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Right Hand Of Darkness (8a)&lt;/em&gt;. Still not able to climb one of
those boulders Patrick and I at least wanted to ascent the uber-famous
&lt;em&gt;Supernova (7c)&lt;/em&gt; while Lukas, having already climbed this gem, wanted to try
&lt;em&gt;Jack The Chipper (7c)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Saturday&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Lukas in Jack The Chipper" src="https://flopska.com/images/DSC_0697.JPG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lukas trying hard: &lt;em&gt;Jack The Chipper (7c)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sunday&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="I in Piranja" src="https://flopska.com/images/DSC_0702.JPG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Myself trying a quite greasy &lt;em&gt;Piranja (7c+)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Monday&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Patrick in U-Boot" src="https://flopska.com/images/DSC_0735.JPG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patrick climbing the super famous &lt;em&gt;U-Boot (6c)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Redis Cluster als Basis für einen verteilten Chat</title><link href="https://flopska.com/redis-cluster-als-basis-fur-einen-verteilten-chat.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-04-03T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2015-04-03T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>flopska</name></author><id>tag:flopska.com,2015-04-03:/redis-cluster-als-basis-fur-einen-verteilten-chat.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Wie schreibt man einen ausfallsicheren Chat für ein Uni-Projekt? Der Post detailliert die mögliche Umsetzung eines verteilten Chat-Systems auf Basis von Redis mit einem Java-Client. Der Load Balancer bleibt als Single Point of Failure - eine mögliche Lösung sind &lt;em&gt;Elastic IP&lt;/em&gt; Adressen.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#anforderungen"&gt;Anforderungen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#stack"&gt;Software Stack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#softwarearchitektur"&gt;Software Architektur&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#hardwarearchitektur"&gt;Hardware Architektur&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="#ausblick"&gt;Ausblick&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Anforderungen &lt;a id="anforderungen"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;mehrere Clients pro Benutzer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrationstest des Servers als Slim Client&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verlauf abrufbar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;verschiedene Server mit Authorisierung (falls einzelne Komponenten ausfallen immer noch lauffähig)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authorisierung an jedem Server möglich&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Persistierung der Nachrichten auf allen Servern/Nodes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;kein Datenschutz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clients pullen, Server pushen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nachrichten so schnell wie möglich auf alle anderen Server&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;alle schreiben an alle (ein "chatroom", broadcast)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Login mit E-Mail und Password&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Software Stack &lt;a id="stack"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://redis.io/"&gt;redis&lt;/a&gt; wird als zentrale Datenbank für die Benutzer und die gesendeten Nachrichten verwendet. Mit redis 3.0.0 ist clustering und somit der verteilte Einsatz in den &lt;em&gt;stable&lt;/em&gt;-Branch gekommen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/xetorthio/jedis"&gt;jedis&lt;/a&gt; ist das empfohlene Java Interface für die Kommunikation mit redis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://restlet.com/"&gt;restlet&lt;/a&gt; stellt ein Framework für RESTful Anwendungen zur Verfügung. Neben dem Server können auch Clients realisiert werden. Diese Funktionalität wird in den Integrationstests verwendet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://junit.org"&gt;junit&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://hamcrest.org/JavaHamcrest/"&gt;hamcrest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://projectlombok.org/"&gt;lombok&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Software Architektur &lt;a id="softwarearchitektur"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mit restlet werden zwei Endpunkte für Anfragen zur Verfügung gestellt:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;http://localhost:8182/user/
http://localhost:8182/message/
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;/user/&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kd"&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kd"&gt;interface&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nc"&gt;RESTUser&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="nd"&gt;@Put&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;json&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;Representation&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;login&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;ChatUser&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;chatUser&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="nd"&gt;@Post&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;json&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;ChatUser&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;createUser&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;ChatUser&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;chatUser&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="o"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Mit der &lt;em&gt;createUser(ChatUser chatUser)&lt;/em&gt; Methode kann ein neuer Benutzer am System registriert werden. Die E-Mail Adresse ist dabei eindeutig, d.h. es kann pro E-Mail Adresse nur einen Benutzer im System geben. Wird der Nutzer angelegt enthält der Rückgabewert die generierte ID und den Authentifizierungsschlüssel des neuen Benutzers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Die &lt;em&gt;login(ChatUser chatUser)&lt;/em&gt; Methode wird zum Einloggen eines Benutzers verwendet. Der Benutzername und das Passwort werden überprüft und bei einer Übereinstimmung wird der entsprechende Authentifizierungsschlüssel als Cookie zurückgegeben. Bei einem Fehler sendet der Server ein HTTP Status &lt;em&gt;401&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;/message/&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kd"&gt;public&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="kd"&gt;interface&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nc"&gt;RESTMessage&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="nd"&gt;@Post&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;json&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;Message&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;sendMessage&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Message&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;message&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="nd"&gt;@Get&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;json&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="n"&gt;List&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;Message&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nf"&gt;readMessages&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;();&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="o"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Das Senden einer Nachricht setzt voraus, dass der Benutzer sich vorher authorisiert hat. Das bedeutet, es muss neben der Nachricht auch ein Cookie mit dem Authentifizierungsschlüssel gesendet werden. War das Senden der Nachricht mit &lt;em&gt;sendMessage(Message message)&lt;/em&gt; erfolgreich enthält die zurückgegebene Nachricht den &lt;em&gt;timestamp&lt;/em&gt;, bei dem die Nachricht am Server eingegangen ist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zum Lesen von Nachrichten ist keine Authentifizierung erforderlich. &lt;em&gt;readMessages&lt;/em&gt; liefert alle auf dem Server gespeicherten Nachrichten zurück.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Hardware Architektur &lt;a id="hardwarearchitektur"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Die Hardware Architektur" src="https://flopska.com/images/chat_architecture.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Der Chat verwendet die klassische Architektur für Webapplikationen: Die Anfragen der Nutzer werden von einem Load Balancer entgegen genommen und auf die Web Server verteilt. Soll eine größere Last verarbeitet werden, können weitere Web Server hinzugefügt werden. Die Authentifizierungsinformationen für Benutzer sind clientseitig in Cookies und serverseitig in der Datenbank gespeichert. Somit hält die Webapplikation keinen State: Fällt ein Server aus routet der Load Balancer die Anfragen an einen anderen Server und der Benutzer bemerkt nichts vom Ausfall eines Servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;redis cluster hat einen Failover Mechanismus eingebaut: Beim Ausfall eines Masters wird automatisch ein bestehender Slave zum Master. In der verwendeten Konfiguration können also im Besten Fall bis zu drei Datenbankserver ausfallen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ausblick &lt;a id="ausblick"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In der oben beschriebenen Konfiguration ist der Load Balancer ein Single Point of Failure. Eine Möglichkeit auf den Ausfall des Load Balancers zu reagieren ist der Einsatz von sogenannten &lt;em&gt;Elastic IP Addresses&lt;/em&gt; (siehe &lt;a href="http://docs.aws.amazon.com/AWSEC2/latest/UserGuide/elastic-ip-addresses-eip.html"&gt;Elastic IP Addresses bei AWS&lt;/a&gt;). Fällt der Load Balancer aus kann seine IP zeitnah einem parallel laufenden Load Balancer zugewiesen werden.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Getting started with vagrant and ansible</title><link href="https://flopska.com/getting-started-with-vagrant-and-ansible.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-04-22T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2014-04-22T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>flopska</name></author><id>tag:flopska.com,2014-04-22:/getting-started-with-vagrant-and-ansible.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A short summary of the steps necessary to install vagrant on a linux box and to start the first virtual machine with a precise32 base image.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://vagrantup.com"&gt;vagrant&lt;/a&gt; is a tool to create and configure reproducible
development environments. Wat?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using virtual machines as your development environment has got multiple
benefits: When you're a developer it's easy to provide every team member with
the same environment. When your a designer you don't have the hassle of setting
up the workspace and can focus on the design instead. When you're done and want
to deploy your software you can use the same process you used to setup your
virtual machines to provision your production system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sounds dope. Where can I get some?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.vagrantup.com/downloads.html"&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt; the vagrant version for
your system and install it. On Ubuntu that's &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;sudo dpkg -i vagrant_1.5.4_x86_64.deb
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Eventually you have to install the virtualbox packages, too. Enter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;sudo apt-get install virtualbox
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;That's it. Now you're ready to setup your first virtual machine. Keep calm, I
will guide you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;vagrant init hashicorp/precise32 
vagrant up
vagrant ssh
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Easy, heh? We just downloaded an Ubuntu precise image, created a so called
&lt;a href="http://docs.vagrantup.com/v2/vagrantfile/index.html"&gt;Vagrantfile&lt;/a&gt;, booted the
machine and connected to it. Halt the machine by disconnecting from the ssh
session and entering &lt;code&gt;vagrant halt&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Speedup Vagrant Execution With a Ramdisk</title><link href="https://flopska.com/speedup-vagrant-execution-with-a-ramdisk.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-04-02T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2014-04-02T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>flopska</name></author><id>tag:flopska.com,2014-04-02:/speedup-vagrant-execution-with-a-ramdisk.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As I am using vagrant for a university project I try to put the virtual machine onto a ramdisk for faster startup times. The post shows that when loading the machine from a ramdisk the startup time does improve. However, the machine itself does not run faster.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Currently I am using &lt;a href="http://www.vagrantup.com/"&gt;vagrant&lt;/a&gt; in conjunction with
&lt;a href="http://www.vagrantup.com/"&gt;ansible&lt;/a&gt; to provide all team members of our
university project with a consistent development and testing environment.
Before I push my changes I want to make sure that every ansible playbook I
wrote is working and idempotent. To achieve this goal I have to test the
scripts a lot and in doing so I spin up a dozen of new machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be able to run the necessary software the machines have to download a lot of
packages. Some are only available as source and have to be compiled. Because
the bottleneck when running the machines often lies within the HDD I thought it
would be nice to speed it up a bit by putting the virtual machines on a
ramdisk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Setting up the ramdisk&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Ubuntu 13.10 'saucy' it is rather simple to set up a ramdisk:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;sudo mkdir /media/ramdisk
sudo mount -t ramfs ramfs /media/ramdisk
sudo chown -R user:group /media/ramdisk
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; Please don't store any important information on the ramdisk as the
data is lost when powering off the computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To automatically mount the partition when booting add this to your
&lt;code&gt;/etc/fstab&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;ramfs       /media/ramdisk      ramfs       defaults        0       0
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;It is not possible to limit the size of the ramdisk. In extreme cases the host
system may run out of memory. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Moving vagrant and virtualbox into the RAM&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vagrant usually stores it's files in &lt;code&gt;~/.vagrant.d/&lt;/code&gt;. To use another path set
the VAGRANT_HOME environment variable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;cp -r ~/.vagrant.d /media/ramdisk/vagrant_home
export VAGRANT_HOME=/media/ramdisk/vagrant_home
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Now you have to change the location of your virtual machines from within
virtualbox. Open the client by entering &lt;code&gt;virtualbox&lt;/code&gt; into the terminal, go to
'File -&amp;gt; Preferences...' and enter your new ramdisk location as 'Default
Machine Folder'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Performance improvements&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;All tests were run with a new Vagrantfile and a 'raring64' box.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start up time without ramdisk:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;time vagrant up
...
vagrant up  2,63s user 1,99s system 12% cpu 35,825 total
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Start up time with ramdisk:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;time vagrant up
...
vagrant up  2,55s user 2,07s system 17% cpu 26,853 total
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;As you can see starting the image from a ramdisk is faster than starting from a
regular HDD. This is the case because vagrant copies the base box (in this case
'raring64') before starting it. However, there are no performance gains while
running the vm (tested with &lt;code&gt;hdparm -Tt /dev/sda&lt;/code&gt;). This is  the case because
virtualbox is already caching the hard drive access into the ram.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>