<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>flopska.com - climbing</title><link href="https://flopska.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://flopska.com/feeds/climbing.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://flopska.com/</id><updated>2015-12-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Next Stop... Fontainebleau</title><link href="https://flopska.com/next-stop-fontainebleau.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-12-18T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-12-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>flopska</name></author><id>tag:flopska.com,2015-12-18:/next-stop-fontainebleau.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;My plan for Fontainebleau was clear: Do something for my Karma and send this boulder from Fred Nicole! Made famous by Ben Moon's and Jerry Moffat's &lt;em&gt;The Real Thing&lt;/em&gt; everyone knows about this kind of special 8a+ in the forest. I wanted to give it a shot at least...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My plan for Fontainebleau was clear: Do something for my Karma and send this boulder from Fred Nicole! Made famous by Ben Moon's and Jerry Moffat's &lt;em&gt;The Real Thing&lt;/em&gt; everyone knows about this kind of special 8a+ in the forest. I wanted to give it a shot at least...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We (Thomas and myself) arrived at Fontainebleau in the dark after a heart-stopping moment where the van got stuck in the wet meadow next to the highway when I tried to turn round because we missed the exit. Luckily Thomas was able to push the car forward till it unstuck. The rest of the drive was boring in comparison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The area is famous for its shit wheather. We experienced it so-so: It didn't rain and the sun came out frequently but somehow a lot of the boulders stayed wet. Appearently it rained &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt; before we arrived and I believe the soaked ground did its magic to keep everything from drying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We still had a lot of fun on the dry or partly dry boulders and Fontainebleau showed us once more just how difficult the different grades are. Being shut down on Karma (I could do the first move but had no chance on the second one) we explored the different areas a bit and tried a lot of the problems in the 5+6 guidebook. Sadly we didn't take many pictures :( For me the best day was the one where we tried to climb the red parcour in the Bas Cuvier area. We didn't manage it completely but the diversity of the problems in the parcour is just awesome: slabs, roofs, vertical climbing and there's even a crack-problem in it. Next time we'll do it fully :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Thomas in Fontainebleau, making quick work of Beatle Juice" src="https://flopska.com/images/thomas_bleau.jpg"&gt;
Thomas making quick work of &lt;em&gt;Beatle Juice 7a+&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our takeaways from the trip: Don't go to the swimming pool in Arbonne-la-forêt to take a shower: It's expensive, they don't allow you to wear regular swimming pants, they don't have nice showers and the pool itself is very small. The shower at &lt;a href="http://www.fontaineblhostel.com/"&gt;Fontaineblhostel&lt;/a&gt; on the other hand is very nice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn't manage to climb Karma, I put three sessions into it but couldn't do the second move. I will come back stronger.    &lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>I am featured in a climbing video?!</title><link href="https://flopska.com/i-am-featured-in-a-climbing-video.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-11-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-11-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>flopska</name></author><id>tag:flopska.com,2015-11-01:/i-am-featured-in-a-climbing-video.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After the trip to Italy I planned to visit a friend in Rosenheim. Driving there I stopped in Chironico and tried some more boulders. I arrived late at night and directly went to sleep. The next morning I got to know some Spaniards living in Zürich and we went to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;After the trip to Italy I planned to visit a friend in Rosenheim. Driving there I stopped in Chironico and tried some more boulders. I arrived late at night and directly went to sleep. The next morning I got to know some Spaniards living in Zürich and we went to try &lt;em&gt;Confessions of a crap artist 7c+&lt;/em&gt;. We did some moves on &lt;em&gt;Matusalem 6c+&lt;/em&gt; to warmup and &lt;a href="Edoardo Moruzzi"&gt;http://www.edoardomoruzzi.com/&lt;/a&gt; captured some of it on video.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/143742361?color=ffffff&amp;portrait=0" width="500" height="281" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://vimeo.com/143742361"&gt;Climbing Vibes&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href="https://vimeo.com/edoardomoruzzi"&gt;Edoardo Moruzzi&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="https://vimeo.com"&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards we drove to the upper area and tried &lt;em&gt;Vitruvian Man&lt;/em&gt; which is a bit of a weird boulder: Someone chipped a large jug into the roof which turned the 7c problem into a 7a-ish one. You can still climb the 7c but you have to use a rather small crimp next to the jug. I climbed the 7a a few years ago so I went for the 7c. Being able to do all of the three single moves I thought it would be easy to link them - somehow the boulder escaped me, though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day I played on &lt;em&gt;Freak Brothers 8a&lt;/em&gt; for a short time but being really exhausted from the trip to Italy and the bouldering the day before I continued my drive to Rosenheim where I was welcomed with an awesome pizza.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Monte Cucco - First visit to Finale and Varazze in Italy</title><link href="https://flopska.com/monte-cucco-first-visit-to-finale-and-varazze-in-italy.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-28T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2015-10-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>flopska</name></author><id>tag:flopska.com,2015-10-28:/monte-cucco-first-visit-to-finale-and-varazze-in-italy.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I bought my Van (a VW T4 Transporter) at the end of September. A few people from the climbing gym in Karlsruhe went to Finale at the start of October and I planned to join them there when I finished my camper conversion. Sebastian, a friend of mine, had some …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I bought my Van (a VW T4 Transporter) at the end of September. A few people from the climbing gym in Karlsruhe went to Finale at the start of October and I planned to join them there when I finished my camper conversion. Sebastian, a friend of mine, had some spare time on his hands and we decided to drive together to Italy.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I raced the camper conversion but it turned out to work well anyways. After an exhausting drive we arrived at the camping in the dark and fell to sleep in an instant. The next morning we met the rest of the people from Karlsruhe and after a short breakfast went climbing together. Having slept only 4 hours our climbing looked more like this:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Resting after a long drive" src="https://flopska.com/images/sebastian_hammock.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We did some easy climbing that day and tried to get used to the rock. The weather was perfect to rest in the sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Varazze&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some climbing the following days a few people decided to drive to Varazze which is around 30 minutes away from the campsite. The picture shows Alex bouldering a 6c on the Gioia boulder which sits right at the beginning of the area.
&lt;img alt="Alex in Varazze" src="https://flopska.com/images/alex_varazze_edited.JPG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We enjoyed some of the easier boulders there and I started to work the moves of &lt;em&gt;Messa Delle Streghe (7c)&lt;/em&gt; which escaped me that day. On a site note it's appearently possible to climb the upper part of the problem, too. When I understand the guidebook correctly it's graded &lt;em&gt;7c+&lt;/em&gt; when you do the highball exit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Finale&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next up was some climbing in the Alveare sector in Finale. The sector is the home of the two famous routes &lt;em&gt;Viaggio Nel Futuro 7c+&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Hyaena 8b/+&lt;/em&gt;. The sun is burning into it so it might be better to go there on a cloudy day but we enjoyed the time in the sun and worked our tan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the guidebook &lt;em&gt;Viaggio&lt;/em&gt; was supposed to be Finale's first 8a but after someone found new beta it turned out to be &lt;em&gt;just&lt;/em&gt; 7c+. I still think it's very hard :).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Trying the super classic viaggio nel Futuro" src="https://flopska.com/images/flo_viaggio_instagram.JPG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the next week I went there two more times but was not able to climb it because I kept falling off the dyno to the huge jug.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the rest of the people from Karlsruhe left for the drive back home I met two guys from Augsburg, Germany: Benny and Chris. It turned out they know the same people in Karlsruhe I know - of course we went climbing together. When we weren't climbing we had awesome meals and some good talks going on.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Short 4 Day Trip To Magic Wood</title><link href="https://flopska.com/short-4-day-trip-to-magic-wood.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-09-06T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2015-09-06T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>flopska</name></author><id>tag:flopska.com,2015-09-06:/short-4-day-trip-to-magic-wood.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Patrick, Lukas and I went to Magic Wood from 24.07 to 27.7 again. Patrick had a
car from his parents and we all had some free time and a lot of psyche to try
ourselves on some of Avers' classics. With the unspoken goal of finally
climbing our …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Patrick, Lukas and I went to Magic Wood from 24.07 to 27.7 again. Patrick had a
car from his parents and we all had some free time and a lot of psyche to try
ourselves on some of Avers' classics. With the unspoken goal of finally
climbing our first 8a we arrived friday noon and set out to try &lt;em&gt;Foxy Lady
(8a)&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Right Hand Of Darkness (8a)&lt;/em&gt;. Still not able to climb one of
those boulders Patrick and I at least wanted to ascent the uber-famous
&lt;em&gt;Supernova (7c)&lt;/em&gt; while Lukas, having already climbed this gem, wanted to try
&lt;em&gt;Jack The Chipper (7c)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Saturday&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Lukas in Jack The Chipper" src="https://flopska.com/images/DSC_0697.JPG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lukas trying hard: &lt;em&gt;Jack The Chipper (7c)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Sunday&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="I in Piranja" src="https://flopska.com/images/DSC_0702.JPG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Myself trying a quite greasy &lt;em&gt;Piranja (7c+)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Monday&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Patrick in U-Boot" src="https://flopska.com/images/DSC_0735.JPG"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patrick climbing the super famous &lt;em&gt;U-Boot (6c)&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>